Register of the Stanley Kuhl Hornbeck papers, 1900-1966
Hoover Institution Archives
Stanley Kuhl Hornbeck papers
1900-1966
67008
Hoover Institution Archives
563 manuscript boxes, 19 card file boxes, 7 oversize boxes, 23 envelopes, 2 oversize folders, 5 sound tape reels, 18 sound discs, memorabilia (250.0 linear feet)
Correspondence, writings, reports, studies, dispatches and instructions, printed matter, memorabilia, photographs, and sound recordings relating to American foreign relations in China, Japan, and other areas of East Asia, political conditions in China and Japan, and Dutch-American relations.
Hornbeck, Stanley Kuhl, 1883-1966.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1967.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1883 May 4 Born, Franklin, Massachusetts
1903 A.B., University of Denver
1904-1907 Rhodes Scholar, Oxford University
1907 B.A., Oxford University
1907-1909 Fellow and Instructor, political science, University of Wisconsin
1909-1913 Instructor in Chinese Government Colleges
1911 Ph.D., University of Wisconsin
1914-1917 Assistant Professor and Associate Professor, political science, University of Wisconsin
1921-1924 Technical Expert, Office of Economic Advisor, U.S. Department of State
1928-1937 Chief, Division of Far Eastern Affairs, U.S. Department of State
1937-1944 Adviser on Political Relations, U.S. Department of State
1944 Director, Office of Far Eastern Affairs, U.S. Department of State
1944 Special Assistant to Secretary of State
1944 Member, American Delegation to Dumbarton Oaks Conference
1944-1947 Ambassador to the Netherlands
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, writings, reports, studies, dispatches and instructions, printed matter, memorabilia, photographs, and sound recordings relating to American foreign relations in China, Japan, and other areas of East Asia, political conditions in China and Japan, and Dutch-American relations.
Note
Some of the documents from this collection were published in 1981 as part of the Hoover Archival Documentaries series in The Diplomacy of Frustration: The Manchurian Crisis of 1931-1933 as Revealed in the Papers of Stanley K. Hornbeck.
Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; United States. Dept. of State.; China--Foreign relations--United States.; China--Politics and government--20th century.; China.; Diplomats--United States.; East Asia--Foreign relations--United States.; East Asia.; Japan--Foreign relations--United States.; Japan--Politics and government--1912-1945.; Japan.; Netherlands--Foreign relations--United States.; Netherlands.; Phonorecords.; Phonotapes.; United States--Foreign relations--China.; United States--Foreign relations--East Asia.; United States--Foreign relations--Japan.; United States--Foreign relations--Netherlands.; United States--Foreign relations.
- Subject and Correspondence File, 1842-1966 (Boxes 1-452)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes of meetings, notes, press releases, clippings, and printed matter, arranged alphabetically by subject and name of correspondent.
  - Abbott, John Jay (Box 1)
  - Abbott, Wilbur C.
  - Abbott, Willis J.
  - Abend, Hallett
  - An Abiding Frontier
  - Academy of Political Science of New York
  - Academy of Political Science, 1966
  - Academy of World Economics
  - Acheson, Dean
  - Achilles, Theodore C.
  - Acker, William R. B.
  - Ackerson, Garret G., Jr.
  - Action, suggested, etc.
  - Adamic, Louis
  - Adams, Senator Alva B.
  - Adams, John
  - Adams, Sherman
  - Adams, Walter A.
  - Adding machine (R. C. Allen), 1955
  - Addresses, material for
  - Adee, Alva
  - Adjustment
  - Admission, 1966
  - Advisors
  - Afghanistan
  - Africa (Box 2)
  - Africa, 1966
  - African Mandates
  - Afro-Asian
  - Aged
  - Agenda Committee
  - Aggression
  - Agreements
  - Agriculture, Department of
  - Ahern, Colonel George P.
  - Aid
  - Aid Refugee Chinese Intellectuals
  - Aikawa, Yoshisuke
  - Air conditioner, Sun radio
  - Air Force
  - Airplanes, 1942 (Box 3)
  - Airplanes, 1943
  - Airplanes, 1944
  - Airpower
  - Air transport
  - Alaska (Box 4)
  - Albania
  - Albert Pike Lodge
  - Albertson, Dean and Compton, Wilson
  - Alburn, Cary R.
  - Alcoh, Eleanor Alcott
  - Aldridge, Clayson W.
  - Alexander, Wallace M.
  - Alfred, Helen
  - Alger, Bruce (Congressman)
  - Alien enemies, treatment of
  - Alien treaty rights, a bill to protect, 1920
  - Aliens, status after war
  - Allen, C. K.
  - Allen, Miss Eleanor W.
  - Allen, Percy F.
  - Allen, Stuart
  - Alliance, Germany-Italy-Japan
  - Alliances
  - Allied and Associated Powers
  - Allied Conference
  - Allies and Alliances
  - Alling, Paul
  - Allinson, Brent Dow
  - Allman, Judge N. F.
  - d'Almeida, T. G. J., 1955
  - Alsop, Joseph
  - Alter, Chester M.
  - Alter, Wilbur
  - Altschul, Frank
  - Alvarez, Alejandro (American Institute of International Law)
  - Ambassador to Netherlands, appointment, clippings, 1944
  - Amerasia
  - Amerasia case
  - America
  - "America," W. A. Slade, Chief Bibliographer
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science, 1954, 1958-1962
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science (Box 5)
  - American Afro-Asian Educational Exchange
  - American-Asian Educational Exchange, Inc. (Liebman)
  - American Asiatic Association
  - American Asiatic Association, 1938 October 20
  - American Asiatic Association (Box 6)
  - American Assembly
  - American Association for the United Nations
  - American Baptist Foreign Mission Society
  - American Bar Associate, 1932
  - American Battle Monuments Commission
  - American Bureau for Medical Aid to China, Inc.
  - American citizens, Japanese assaults upon
  - American claims
  - American Coalition of Patriotic Societies
  - American Committee for International Studies, Princeton, New Jersey
  - American Committee for Non-Participation in Japanese Aggression
  - American Conservative Union, 1964 December
  - American consular offices
  - American Council on Education (Box 7)
  - American Council of Learned Societies
  - American Council on Public Affairs
  - American Far Eastern Association
  - American firms and interests
  - American foreign policy
  - American Foreign Service Association
  - American Foreign Service Journal, S. K. H. Review
  - American Friends of China, Dr. Berthould Laufer, Chicago, 1929 November
  - American Geographical Society
  - American Historical Association
  - American history, bibliography
  - American Institute of Pacific Relations, Inc.
  - American International Corporation and the Adams Express Company
  - American Journal of International Law
  - American Law Institute
  - American Legion
  - American Legion, Augustus P. Gardner, Post No. 18
  - Americans living abroad (Box 8)
  - American missions (missionaries)
  - American Palestine Committee
  - American Peace Society
  - American Polish Chamber of Commerce in the U.S., Inc.
  - American Political Science Association
  - American Political Science Association (Box 9)
  - American President Lines
  - American prosperity
  - American Red Cross
  - American Republics
  - American Republics, division of, survey of policy
  - American Security Council
  - American Society of International Law
  - American Society of International Law (Box 10)
  - American Society of International Law, 1964-1966 (Box 11)
  - American Society of International Law, committee
  - American Society of International Law, constitution
  - American University
  - American University, 1932, 1934, 1938
  - American University, Correspondence with President Anderson and E. Griffith, 1961 January
  - American University, School of International Service
  - American Oriental Society, 1936
  - American Year Book, Schuyler-Hart, 1934
  - American Youth Hostels
  - Americans for Constitutional Action
  - Americans for Democratic Action
  - Americans for Reappraisal of Far Eastern Policy, Yale, 1966
  - Amerman, Richard H., Major, 1961-
  - Ames, Dr. Joseph Sweetman
  - Ancell, Robert M., Jr.
  - Anderson, Allen G.
  - Anderson, Arthur M.
  - Anderson, Frederick D.
  - Anderson, G. E.
  - Angelino, A. D. A. de Kab
  - Angkor
  - Anglo-Japanese Alliance (Box 12)
  - Anglo-Japanese Alliance Treaties
  - Anglo-Japanese Alliance: Is There an Arbitration Treaty between U.S. & G.B.?
  - Anglo-Japanese Alliance: British View in Far East
  - Anglo-Japanese Alliance, miscellaneous
  - Anglo-Japanese Alliance, special memo
  - Anglo-Japanese Alliance (Box 13)
  - Annals of American Academy of Political and Social Science, China Number (Box 14)
  - Annuities, Sweet Briar Salvation Army
  - Ansell, Brigadier General Samuel T.
  - Anzac
  - Anzus (Australia, New Zealand, United States)
  - Appam Case
  - Appeasement
  - Appleby, Paul H.
  - Appleton and Company
  - Appleton and Company Royalty Statements
  - Applications
  - Appointment as Ambassador, congratulations, etc., 1944 September
  - Arabs (Box 15)
  - Araki
  - Archbold, Anne
  - Archdeacon, Eric L. F.
  - Arctic
  - Argelander, F.
  - Argentina
  - Arita, Hachiro
  - Arizona Incident
  - Armaments
  - Armed Forces, 1933-1943
  - Armed Forces, movement of troops
  - Armed Forces, Russia
  - Armed Merchantmen
  - Arming submarines, President's authority (Box 16)
  - Armistice, 1918
  - Armistice Proposals of February 29, 1932
  - Armour, Norman
  - Arms and ammunition, export of
  - Arms Conference, 1921-1922
  - Arms and disarmament
  - Arms embargo
  - Arms exports
  - Arms and munitions controversy
  - Arms Traffic Convention, comments on
  - Armstrong, Edward (Box 17)
  - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish, 1955
  - Armstrong, O. K.
  - Armstrong, William Campbell
  - Army
  - Army Active Duty, 1927
  - Army Active Duty, "Report on Mechanization in British Army," by S. K. Hornbeck, 1931
  - Army and Navy Club
  - Army correspondence course
  - Army Military Intelligence materials
  - Army Military Intelligence promotion
  - Army Military Intelligence Reserve List (Box 18)
  - Army Reserve Corps, Military Intelligence
  - Army translation of French book
  - Army-Navy Staff College Speech, 1944 May 20
  - Army-Navy Staff College Speech, 1944 August 9
  - Army-Navy, Unification
  - Army, U.S.
  - Army War College
  - Army War College, G-2 Course, 1923-1927
  - Army War College Report on Military Raw Material: Petroleum, Mineral Oil, 1923
  - Arndt, Christian O. (Box 19)
  - Arnett, Eugene
  - Arnold, H.
  - Arnold, General Henry H.
  - Arnold, Julean
  - Arnold, M.
  - Arsenal of Democracy
  - Arts Club, 1932
  - Asada, Sadao (Washington Conference)
  - Ashby, Stanley R.
  - Ashurst, Senator Henry F.
  - Asia
  - Asia (a journal)
  - Asia Foundation
  - Asia Letter
  - Asia Society
  - Asian and Pacific Council
  - Asian Student, The
  - Asian Survey
  - Asiatic Squadron (Box 20)
  - Association for Asian Studies, 1960-1965
  - Assurances, Japan and China, 1937
  - Astor, William
  - Atcheson, George, Jr. (Box 21)
  - Atherton, Ray
  - Athey, Ralph
  - Atlantic Council of the USA, Inc.
  - Atrocities
  - Attrition
  - Atwater, Charles W.
  - Atwood, Albert W.
  - Auld, George P.
  - Austin, Senator Warren R.
  - Australia (Box 22)
  - Australia, 1938-1945, 1960-1966
  - Australian Legation
  - Austrian Treaty
  - Austrian Treaty objections
  - Austrian Treaty, proposals regarding China
  - Austro - German Customs Union
  - Authors Club (Box 23)
  - Authors' League
  - Automobile Insurance, and Repairs
  - Auto Insurance and Registration, Massachusetts
  - Automobile Owner's Association, Incorporated
  - Auxier, George W.
  - Avery, Eunice Harnet
  - Aviation
  - Aviation, Pacific Ocean
  - Axis
  - Aydelotte, Frank
  - Aydelotte, Frank (Special - July 1954)
  - Aydelotte, Frank, 1956
  - Aydt, A. E.
  - Ayers
  - Ayers, Brig. Gen. Leonard P.
  - Babcock, Robert S. (Box 24)
  - Babcock, W. R.
  - Babson, Daniel L.
  - Babson, Roger W.
  - Bachrach Studio, Inc.
  - Bacon, R. E.
  - Badger, Richard
  - Badger Quarterly, The
  - Baerensprung, Horst Wolfgang
  - Baggaley, Captain William (U.S.N.)
  - Baghdad
  - Bailie, J.
  - Bailey, Norman A.
  - Baily, H. J.
  - Bain, H. F.
  - Baird, Edwin
  - Baird, Joseph H.
  - Baird, William Raimond
  - Bakeless, John
  - Bakenhus, Rear Admiral R. E.
  - Baker, C. F.
  - Baker, E. Carlton
  - Baker, Frances
  - Baker, John Earl
  - Baker, James C.
  - Baker, James M.
  - Baker, Newton D.
  - Baker, Stannard
  - Bakhuis, E. E.
  - Baldwin, G. H.
  - Baldwin, Hanson W.
  - Baldwin, Joseph Clark
  - Baldwin, Karl F.
  - Baldwin, Laverne
  - Baldwin, Roger L.
  - Baldwin, Stanley (Prime Minister of England)
  - Baldwin - Wallace College, 1958
  - Balfour, Arthur James
  - Ball, Mrs. William
  - Ballantine, Joseph W.
  - Ballantine, Joseph W., 1955-1966
  - Ballantine, Joseph W., on U.S. policy
  - Balli, Fritz
  - Baltimore '29 Club, 1932 January 22
  - Baltimore, (Mrs. H. O. Schloss), 1931 (Box 25)
  - Baltimore Sun
  - Bamboo Curtain
  - Bancroft, Alice H.
  - Bandits
  - Bandung
  - Banister, Marion
  - Banking institutions, American and foreign affiliations
  - Banks, Will K.
  - Bar examination regulations
  - Barber, Columbus S.
  - Barber, Helen
  - Barber and Rhodes Scholarship articles
  - Barefoot, T. A. B.
  - Barends, B.
  - Barghoorn, Professor Frederick
  - Barkalow - Carter Wedding, 1891
  - Barnard, Lieutenant Colonel Joseph H.
  - Barnes, George and Myrtle and son Robert
  - Barnes, George, obituary
  - Barnes, Walter C.
  - Barnett, A. Doak
  - Barnett, Eugene E.
  - Barnett, Eugene E., memorandum
  - Barnett, Mrs. George, pictures and books
  - Barnett, Robert W.
  - Barrett, Mrs. John Walton
  - Barrett, Willis C.
  - Barron, Bryton
  - Barron, Carter
  - Barron, Nancy M.
  - Barrows, David P.
  - Barry, J. P.
  - Bartlett, D. F.
  - Bartley, Mr. Numan V.
  - Baruch, Bernard
  - Baruch, Herman B.
  - Bashford, Bishop James W.
  - Bassett, Amy and Prentiss
  - Bassett, Mrs. Prentiss
  - Batchelder, Charles C.
  - Bates, M. S.
  - Battle, J. M.
  - Bau, Joshua
  - Baum, H. and son
  - Baxter, James
  - Bay, Charles A.
  - Bayley, Miss Florence T.
  - Beale, Betty
  - Beall, J. Glenn (Senator from Maryland)
  - Beardstown
  - Beasley, Steven E.
  - Beaufort, Madame de
  - Beaulieu Vineyard Distributing Co.
  - Beaumont, Brigadier General John C.
  - Beauvoir, Simone de
  - Bebb, Colonel
  - Beck, E. S. Esquire
  - Beck, William (Box 26)
  - Becker, Carl L.
  - Beenhouwer, Harold
  - Beer, George Louis
  - Beer, George Louis, "German Colonies in Africa"
  - Beers, Prof. Burton F.
  - Begg, John M.
  - Beggs, Gertrude H.
  - Behenna, Vivian M.
  - Behn, Sosthenes
  - Behr, Karl H.
  - Belcher, W. E.
  - Belgian Embassy
  - Belgian "Invasion," legal aspects
  - Belgium
  - Belgium, deportation from, 1916
  - Bell, Daniel W.
  - Bell, Edward A.
  - Bell, Edward Price
  - Bell, J. C.
  - Bellamy, R. V. Esquire
  - Beloit
  - Beloit College (Washington Alumni)
  - Bemis, Samuel Flagg
  - Benesh, Florentine
  - Benninghoff, H. Merrell
  - Benson, Henry K.
  - Benton, J. W.
  - Benton, William
  - Berding, Andrew
  - Berding, Andrue
  - Berger, David C.
  - Bergman, Elizabeth
  - Bergman, Maxwell
  - Berkes, Carolyn North
  - Berks, Maj. Jesse
  - Berkson, Seymour
  - Berle, Adolf A., Jr.
  - Berle, Adolf A., 1938-1941
  - Berle, Adolf A., 1924-1944 (Box 27)
  - Berlin
  - Berlock Company, Inc.
  - Bernard, Robert J.
  - Bernstein, J. H.
  - Berry, Frank N.
  - Bess, Demaree, 1955
  - Beta Theta Pi, (Mackinac), 1956
  - Beta Theta Pi, (Poland Springs) (Irwin), 1956-1957
  - Beta Theta Pi, 1957-1958
  - Beta Theta Pi, 1963
  - Beth-El General Hospital
  - Bethune, John T., Secretary
  - Bettelheim, Edwin S.
  - Beukema, Col. Herman
  - Bevan, Ralph H., articles by
  - Bevis, Palmer
  - Beynen-Yeaman, M. M. P.
  - Bhutan, 1958
  - Bibbings, Vivian Linderman
  - Bible
  - Bible, Frank W.
  - Bibliography (Box 28)
  - Bibliography, books
  - Bibliography, One Hundred Choice Books
  - Bicycle stolen
  - Biddle, Eric
  - Biddle, Samuel
  - Biddle, William W.
  - Bidwell, P. W.
  - Bien, Miss Bettina
  - Big Four
  - Bigelow, Donald F.
  - Biggerstaff, Knight
  - Bilgrey, Felix J.
  - Bills of Rights
  - Binder, Carroll
  - Binger, Carl
  - Bingham, Hiram ("Harry")
  - Bingham, Joseph Walter
  - Bingham, Woodbridge
  - Biography
  - Birch Society
  - Bird, Howard
  - Bird, Remsen D.
  - Bird, Theodore
  - Birdsall, Paul
  - Birdwood, Lord
  - Birge, Anna G.
  - Birthday, S. K. Hornbeck, 1956, 1960
  - Bishop, C. W.
  - Bishop, Dorothy
  - Bishop, Max
  - Bishop, Ralph C.
  - Bishop, Rufus Walter
  - Bissell, Clayton L.
  - Bisson, T. A.
  - Black Chamber
  - Black, Colonel Edwin F.
  - Black, P. R.
  - Black, Colonel Ira W.
  - Blake, M. Williams
  - Blake, R. P.
  - Blakeman, Edward W.
  - Blakeney, Charles
  - Blakeslee, George H., 1929-1944 (Box 29)
  - Blakeslee, George H., Lytton Commission
  - Blakeslee, George H. (Box 30)
  - Blakeslee, Edna
  - Bland, Neville (Box 31)
  - Blank, Earl W.
  - Bleyer, Professor
  - Bliss, Elmer Jared
  - Bliss, Mildred
  - Bliss, Robert-Woods
  - Bliven, Bruce
  - Block, Ilse
  - Blockade
  - Blockade and continuous voyages
  - Blockade, Law of
  - Blockade in modern war
  - Bloeme, M. de
  - Blohm, Lee R.
  - Blok, P. R.
  - Blom, J. J. F.
  - Bloom, Sol
  - Bloom, Sol, radio addresses
  - Blue Book of America, 1959
  - Blumberger, Heer, J. Th. P.
  - Boal, Pierre de L.
  - Board of Economic Warfare
  - Board, National Labor Relations
  - Boat Race Dinner
  - Bobbs Merrill Co.
  - Bodde, J. W.
  - Bodde, Theodore
  - Bodger, John D.
  - Boehme, Harry C.
  - Boekery, Comm. Venn de
  - Boetzelaer, van Ousterhourt, Baron C. G. W. H.
  - Boggs, S Whittemore
  - Bogan, L. C.
  - Bohlen, Charles E.
  - Bohemian Grove
  - Bollenbeck, Capt. Joseph A.
  - Bolling, General
  - Bolt, H.
  - Bom, Jan
  - Bomb
  - Bombing, aerial
  - Bonbright, James C. H.
  - Bond, W. L.
  - Boner
  - Bonnett, Mrs. John R. and Martha
  - Bonsal, Stephen
  - Boobs
  - Book Reviews, 1934-1941
  - Book, Review, 1942 (Box 32)
  - Book Reviews, 1943-1944 (Box 33)
  - Book Reviews
  - Books
  - Books, 1966
  - Books, for
  - Bookplates, labels and gadgets
  - Book sales
  - "Bookself of America,", 1953
  - Boom, Captain Wilhelm, 1962-
  - Boot, Gerald M.
  - Borah, Senator (Box 34)
  - Borah, Senator William, letter to
  - Borchard, Edwin M.
  - Borchardt, Selma M.
  - Borden, Sir Robert
  - Boreel, Jhr. Willem
  - Borg, Dorothy
  - Borie, W. Adolphe E.
  - Borneo
  - Borthwick
  - Bosch, H. van den
  - Boston, J. W.
  - Bourne, Henry E.
  - Bousios, Basil Nicholas Hellenagoras
  - Bouwman, J.
  - Bovenkamp, Miss N. A. H. van den
  - Bowles, Chester
  - Bowles, Chester, on China problem
  - Bowman, Isaiah
  - Boxer Indemnity
  - Boy Scouts of America
  - Boyce, Richard F.
  - Boyd, Allen D.
  - Boyd - Carpenter
  - Boyd, William K.
  - Boyden, William L.
  - Boyer, Esther W.
  - Boynton, Charles L.
  - Boynton, Grace M.
  - Braddick, Prof. H. B.
  - Bradley, F. J.
  - Brady, Admiral Parke H.
  - Brady, Robert A.
  - Bragonier, Reg
  - Branch, J. R. Bromwell
  - Brandt, George L.
  - Brandt, Karl
  - Brane, Dennis
  - Branscomb, Harvie
  - Brant, Irving
  - Bratter, Herbert M.
  - Bratton, Colonel Rufus F.
  - Brauer, William Wallace
  - Braun, Henry
  - Brazil (Box 35)
  - Brazilian Embassy, Ambassador, Moww, 1964 December
  - Brazilian Ambassador's Dinner to President Hoover, 1930 June 14
  - Brazilian Legation
  - Breakey, Daisy M.
  - Breght, James van
  - Brentano's
  - Brett, Homer, Jr.
  - Brewer, F. A. and Company
  - Brewster, Mary Blackmen
  - Brewster, Mrs. Owen
  - Bricker Amendment
  - Brickner, Richard M.
  - Briggs, Ellis O.
  - Briggs, Herbert W.
  - Brink, Louise
  - Brinkley, Florence
  - Bristol, Mark L.
  - Britain and America, Meany et al.
  - British Aircraft Constructors, Ltd.
  - British Broadcasting Corporation
  - British Colonial Commercial Policy
  - British Embassy
  - British Empire Preferences
  - British Institute of International Affairs, The
  - British Library of Information
  - Britten, Fred A.
  - Broadbent, Frank C., Lieutenant
  - Brockman, Fletcher S.
  - Brodie, Donald M.
  - Brodie, Edward E.
  - Broek, J. van den
  - Brokmeyer, Eugene C.
  - Bronson, Eugene V.
  - Brooke, Miss Marjorie van de Water (Box 36)
  - Brookings Institution, 1948, 1952, 1956
  - Brookings Seminar (Lake Forest), 1949
  - Brooks, Preston
  - Brooks, Rev. Dr. Seth R.
  - Browder, Earl
  - Browder, Earl and Welles, 1942
  - Brown and Williamson Tobacco Company
  - Brown, Constantine
  - Brown, Harrison
  - Brown, Philip Marshall
  - Brown, Ray
  - Brown, Thad H.
  - Browne, Sidney H. (Mrs.)
  - Brownlow, Louis
  - Bruce, David K. E.
  - Brucholz, Henry V.
  - Brunauer, Ester Caukin, Mrs.
  - Brussels Conference by Tsien Tai (Box 37)
  - Brussels Conference, 1937
  - Drafts of Mr. Davis' Opening Speech
  - Drafts of Report and Declaration of November 24, 1937
  - Drafts of Resolution of November 15, 1937
  - Minutes of the First-Fifth Meetings
  - Documents (Box 38)
  - Minutes of Sixth-Tenth Meetings
  - Memoranda and clippings (Box 39)
  - Brunauer, Mrs. Stephen (Box 40)
  - De Bruyn, Dr. William F.
  - Bryan, Lieutenant Commander Hamilton V. (U.S.N.)
  - Bryan, Robert T.
  - Bryan, William Jennings
  - Bryn-Jones, David
  - Butchtel and Travers
  - Buchtel, Henry Augustus
  - Buchtel, William
  - Buck, J. Lossing
  - Buck, Pearl S.
  - Buck, Philo M.
  - Bucknell, Howard
  - Buddhism
  - Budget
  - Buell, Raymond Leslie
  - Buell, Raymond Leslie, articles by
  - Buffington, Joseph
  - Buhite, Russell D.
  - Buholzer, Fridolin A.
  - Buhrman, Parker W.
  - Bulbs, Dutch
  - Bulgarian Legation
  - Bulgarian Situation by Grace Tytus McLennan
  - Bull, Benjamin H.
  - Bullard, Arthur
  - Bullitt, William C. (Box 41)
  - Bullitt, Secretary of State William C., 1941
  - Bullitt, William, Report on China, 1947 October
  - Bullitt, the Honorable William C., 1952-1966
  - Bumblebee, The (Box 42)
  - Bundy, Harvey H.
  - Bundy, William P. and McGeorge
  - Bunker, Frank F.
  - Bunyon, Paul, Wonderful Life and Deeds of _____, By Hubert Langerock
  - Burdet, R.
  - Burdett, William C.
  - Burdick, Don
  - Burdick, Marc
  - Bureau of the Budget
  - Bureaucracy
  - Burgess, H. D. R.
  - Burgess, Kenneth F.
  - Burgess, John Stewart
  - Burgher, Robert
  - Burke, Admiral
  - Burke, Gordon L.
  - Burke, Reverend John J.
  - Burke, Thomas
  - Burke, William B.
  - Burks, Ardath W.
  - Burlingame, Anson
  - Burma
  - Burma Road
  - Burnes, Mrs. May Raymond
  - Burnett, Charles
  - Burns, Richard D.
  - Burns, Robert E., 1966
  - Burt, Colonel W. H.
  - Burton, Mr. Justice Harold H.
  - Burton, Father Spence
  - Business Week Magazine
  - Buss, Claude A.
  - Bussy, Aide
  - Butler, Frederic Bates
  - Butler, George H.
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray
  - Butow, Robert, Princeton, 1962 September
  - Butow and Joseph W. Ballantine
  - Butrick, Richard P.
  - Butterworth, regarding U.S. - China Policy
  - Butterworth, Memo to. On China Policy, 1948-
  - Buurman, L.
  - Byas, Hugh
  - Bynner, Witter
  - Byrd, Richard E., flights of
  - Byrd, Senator Robert C. and Senator Harry C. Byrd
  - Byrne, Thad.
  - Byrnes, James F.